Ann-Cathrin Will

New Haw, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com

Profile

Experienced front-end developer with strong skills in HMTL5 and CSS3 coming from an agency background. I enjoy a challenge and look for the opportunity to expand and develop my skill sets.

My most recent portfolio of work is available at: www.cathrinwill.com

Technical Skills

Core Skills

- XHTML/HTML5(Excellent)
- CSS/3(Excellent)
- JavaScript / JQuery (Satisfactory)
 Usability
- AJAX(Learning)
- PHP(Basic)
- SQL(Basic)
- XML(Basic)

Techniques

- Web Standards
- W3C Accessibility Guidelines
- Cross-browser compatibility

Programs

- Adobe Photoshop
- SublimeText2
- FileZilla
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

Professional Experience

Front end Developer at Purple Agency

March 2013 – Present

Front end Developer at Webexpectations

September 2012 – March 2013

- Worked on a variety of projects building the frontend from Photoshop templates, making changes to existing websites and creating standalone pages for multivariate testing.
- Experience gained from working with a variety of CMS's including Joomla, Wordpress and Magento.
- Working with development processes including Git for version control.
- Acquired basic experience with responsive web development and mobile optimised websites and a basic knowledge foundation on retina display development.
- Developed several HTML Emails and HTML email signatures.
- Clients I have done work for include: Mizuno Golf, Loreal, MayfairSuites, Carte Blanche Greetings, Premium Tours, Ragus, Bissell, PetrolHeads, Bucks&Berks and Mobility Scooters Plus. For more information on what I did you can look at my online portfolio.

Night Receptionist at Premier Inn

September 2009 – September 2012

Junior Web Developer at SuperReal GmbH, Germany April 2007 – October 2007

- Worked on Individual Projects from Graphical design to upload.
- Worked in a team with Backend Developers and Graphic Designers.
- Updated existing websites and XML templates.
- Learned Photoshop, improved on HTML and CSS.
- Ensured websites were identical across browsers.

Ann-Cathrin Will

New Haw, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com

• Was flexible to work overtime in order to quickly meet deadlines.

Education

Web Development with Business BSc (Hons), Kingston University 2009 – 2012

- Learned the foundations to several previously self-taught languages.
- Improved and learnt several new languages.
- Worked in a lot of groups often taking on the role of organiser within it.
- Always ensured to hand in every coursework before the deadline.
- Helped peers with their work, and vice versa learned a lot from others.
- Thoroughly enjoyed working on the Single Semester Final Year Project and was proud of the end result, which can be viewed on http://pixxy.cathrinwill.com/

Computer Information Systems and Mathematics Foundation

2008 - 2009

Kingston College, Kingston upon Thames

Whitbread Group Plc

2010

Front Office - Edexcel Level 2 NVQ Adult Numeracy - Edexcel Level 2 NVQ Adult Literacy - Edexcel Level 2 NVQ

GCE 'A' Levels, Strode's College, Egham

2004 - 2005

A - German (A2) E - Biology (AS)

D - Psychology (AS) B - General Studies (GCSE)

GCSEs, Langley Grammar, Slough

1999 - 2004

11 GCSEs – including Maths and English Grade C and above

Interests

Apart from keeping up to date with anything surrounding web development by subscribing to a number of blogs, I greatly enjoy sunshine, travelling, psychology and reading, although mostly online nowadays.

Languages

English (Bilingual proficiency)
German (Bilingual proficiency)

References

Available on request.